bontrager.com 2008-09-13

# Bontrager: Support — Privacy Policy

This website is owned and operated by Trek Bicycle Corporation. Your privacy on the Internet is important to us. As a part of the operation of the Bontrager site, we gather certain types of information about users. We want you to know the types of information we gather and what we do with it.

### Information Collected By Trek

Trek and eTrek LLC (which operates the Trek Store and eTrek Auction portions of the site) collect two general types of information from users: personal data (such as names and e-mail addresses); and aggregated data (such as information about traffic patterns on the Bontrager site; for example, how many users log into the Bontrager site on a daily basis).

### Personal Data

Personal data is collected when users provide information to Trek or eTrek LLC, for example in registering for electronic newsletters or other membership services, in answering surveys, purchasing items from The Trek Store, registering to bid on items available at an eTrek Auction, and/or registering for contests and other promotional opportunities provided by Trek. When you register or request information on the site, we generally need you to provide your name, e-mail address, mailing address, day phone number and credit card information (only when ordering products at The Trek Store), as well as create a username and password. In addition, if you send us personal correspondence, such as e-mails or letters, we may collect such information into a file specific to you.

### Aggregated Information and Usage Information

Aggregated information, such as which page users access and information volunteered by users, such as survey information and/or site registration information, is collected through various methods. In the course of using our site, we also automatically track certain information about you. This information includes the URL that you just came from, which URL you next go to, what browser you are using, and your IP address. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you're surfing the Web. Web servers, the computers that "serve up" Web pages, automatically identify your computer by its IP address, and when you request a page from Trek, our servers log your IP address. Trek does not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, so although your session will be logged, you will remain anonymous to us.

### Use of Cookies

The Bontrager site also uses "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that most major web sites write to your hard drive for record keeping purposes when you visit them. Cookies allow Trek and eTrek LLC to measure activity on the various areas of the Bontrager site and to improve your user experience, for example by remembering your passwords and viewing preferences, thus allowing you to visit various parts of the Bontrager site without re-registering. Cookies are also used by Trek and eTrek LLC to measure activity on the site and make improvements and updates based on which areas are popular and which are not. We do not use cookies to retrieve information from your computer that was not originally sent in a cookie. Please note: except for personal information voluntarily provided by you (e.g., during membership registration or a contest), Trek does not use information transferred through cookies for any promotional or marketing purposes, nor is that information shared with any third parties whatsoever. You may occasionally get cookies from our advertisers, which is standard in the Internet industry. Trek does not control these cookies, and these cookies are not subject to Trek's privacy policies.

Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you when cookies are being sent. However, it is possible that some parts of a site, such as a member-only area and shopping, contest and game areas, will not function properly if you do so.

### Use of Information Collected by Trek

Trek uses both the personal and aggregated and usage information we collect for multiple purposes. For example, we collect this information for fulfilling orders and prizes, administering information requests and providing information services, tracking/verifying compliance with Trek policies as well as federal, state and local laws, and for editorial and feedback solicitation purposes. We may use your e-mail address and, in rare situations, your mailing address or phone number, to contact you regarding customer service issues or billing matters. Personal and aggregated information is also used to: improve the content of the Trek Store; perform system administration activities; customize the content and/or layout of the Trek Store for each individual user; and notify users about updates to the Trek Store or promotional offers or opportunities that we believe will be of interest to you. We will always try to provide you with an opportunity to decline this service when such information is requested from you online. If you later decide you would rather not receive this information, or would like to opt-out of any other information request or distribution, you may also update your Account Information on the applicable portion of the Bontrager site or simply reply to any Trek e-mail sent to you and type UNSUBSCRIBE as the subject of your reply or in the message of the e-mail. We may also use your information and activity on the site to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems and enforce our Terms of Use.

### Disclosure of Collected Information to Third Parties

Trek and eTrek LLC do not sell, trade or rent your personal data to third parties without prior permission from you. (Please note that the term "third party" does not include web site hosting partners and other parties who assist Trek and eTrek LLC in operating the Bontrager site, as long as such parties have signed confidentiality agreements obligating them to keep user data confidential.) Trek may share your data, however, in an aggregated information, as well as aggregated usage information, with third parties for both advertising and promotional purposes. Further, we cooperate with all law enforcement inquires, and with all third parties, to enforce their intellectual property or other legal rights.

### Links to Other Sites

It is important to note that the Bontrager site might contain links to other sites, and that those sites may not follow the same privacy policies as Trek. For instance, if you clicked on an advertisement on The Trek Store, this might take you away from the Bontrager site and to an entirely different site. This includes links to advertisers, Trek dealers, content providers, and business partners, who may use Trek's name and/or logos as a result of a co-branding or other agreement. These sites may send their own cookies to you, and may collect data and make uses of it that Trek would not. Neither Trek nor eTrek LLC controls these sites or uses, or bears any responsibility or liability for them.

### Security

The security of all personally identifiable information associated with users of the Bontrager site is of great concern to us. Trek implements a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. Once we receive your transmission, we use our reasonable best efforts to ensure its security on our systems. When credit card information is transmitted, we use SSL (secure socket layer) encryption technology. Any Account information you enter on the Bontrager site is password-protected so that only you can access it. You should not divulge your password or user identification number to anyone. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Trek and eTrek LLC can't ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk.

### Terms and Conditions

Please also visit Trek's Terms of Use governing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability applicable to your use of the Bontrager web site.

### Your Acceptance of these Terms

By using the Bontrager site, you signify your agreement to this Privacy Statement. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site. Trek reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time. It is your responsibility to review this policy from time to time to be familiar with changes. At the beginning of the policy, we will endeavor to post the date on which it was last updated.
